Guide to YOST: Y / Opera / Studies Today
YOST: Y / Opera / Studies Today
Oral History of American Music
YOST: Y / Opera / Studies Today
2020 2021
YOST
Oral History of American Music
12 Computer Files
25.74 gigabytes
Kreuzer, Gundula Katharina
Scope and Contents
A collection of recorded conferences, workshops and presentations hosted by the Yale Opera Studies initiative.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
mp4 and mov files
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by the order in which panels and workshops were presented.
Opera; Women in music
- Developing Opera in the Age of #MeToo, 2020 May 8; Kreuzer, Gundula Katharina
  Content description
  The 2020 annual Y / Opera / Studies Today conference of the Yale Department of Music: Developing Opera in the Age of #MeToo, presented via webinar on May 5, 2020
  - Composing Women's Issues, 2020 May 8; YOST 1 a; Reid, Ellen (Composer); Mazzoli, Missy (1980-10-27-); Cusick, Suzanne G.; Ellison, Cori; 1 Computer File; 4.44 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 67 mins
    Conference location:
    Conference convened via videochat, organized in New Haven, CT
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    mov file
    Conditions Governing Access
    As a preservation measure, original computer files may not be used. Digital access copies must be provided for use.
  - Developing New Opera, 2020 May 8; YOST 1 b; Kreuzer, Gundula Katharina; Cremo, Paul; Harrington, Wendall; Mazzoli, Missy (1980-10-27-); Morrison, Beth; Osgood, Steven; Reid, Ellen (Composer); Tesori, Jeanine; Zambello, Francesca; 1 Computer File; 4.44 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 116 mins
    Conference convened via videochat, with organizers in New Haven, CT.
  - Salt: A Workshop Exploration of the Online Possibilities of Opera, 2020 May 8; YOST 1 c; Diamond, Patrick (Theater Director); Calcagno, Mauro (Musicologist); Brunelle, Jill; Gambini, Danilo; Pollock, Frances; Roller, Emily; Tassi, Camilla (Projection Designer); 1 Computer File; 1.52 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 102 mins
    Conference convened via videochat, with organizers located in New Haven, CT.
    mp4 file
    General
    Former child record (uri=/repositories/7/digital_objects/130839 - title=[Preservica - video] YOST 1 c) was deleted from catalogue on [Fri Jun 12 16:42:57 EDT 2020] as matching Preservica null 2ea981b0-dd0d-48e6-9f9a-f65b5daac5e3 was deleted.
- Opera and Representation, 2021 May 6 2021 May 8; Kreuzer, Gundula Katharina
  Content Description
  The 2021 annual Y / Opera / Studies Today conference of the Yale Department of Music: Opera and Representation, presented via webinar on May 6 and May 8, 2021
  - Director's Commentary: The Industry's Sweet Land (Los Angeles, 2020), 2021 May 6; YOST 2 a; Sharon, Yuval; 1 Computer File; 1.06 gigabytes; Running time: approximately 92 mins
    Location
    .mp4 file
  - Welcome and Introduction, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 b i; Kreuzer, Gundula Katharina; 1 Computer File; 128 megabytes; Approximate running time: 13 mins
  - Lightning Talks I: Casting Aida - "My Skin Was My Costume": Blackness and Aida, 1925-1933, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 b ii; Caplan, Lucy; Zabala, Adriana; 1 Computer File; 66.1 megabytes; Approximate running time: 12 mins
    This material is restricted. Access may be granted to a patron who has obtained direct permission from the presenter or their estate.
  - Lightning Talks I: Casting Aida - Before the Met: Leontyne Price, Television, and the NBC Opera Theater, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 b iii; Ward-Griffin, Danielle; Zabala, Adriana; 1 Computer File; 58.5 megabytes; Approximate running time: 11 mins
  - Lightning Talks I: Casting Aida - Join the Chorus of Voices: Opera, Identity, and the Social Media Moment, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 b iv; Mosley, Imani Danielle; Zabala, Adriana; 1 Computer File; 105 megabytes; Approximate running time: 9 mins
    .mp4 files
  - Lightning Talks I: Casting Aida - Discussion, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 b v; Gibson, Maya; Caplan, Lucy; Ward-Griffin, Danielle; Mosley, Imani Danielle; 1 Computer File; 258 megabytes; Approximate running time: 23 mins
  - Lightning Talks II: Challenging Stories, Staging, (Dis)Appearance, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 b vi; Calico, Joy Haslam, 1965-; Ebright, Ryan; Everett, Yayoi Uno; Steigerwald Ille, Megan, 1987-; Sheppard, William Anthony, 1969-; 1 Computer File; 615 megabytes; Approximate running time: 62 minutes
    Scope and Contents
    Includes introduction, three lightning talks, and discussion. Lightning talk titles: Reinventing Malcolm, Redefining Opera: Anthony Davis's X (Ryan Ebright), Saariaho and Sellars's Only the Sound Remains (2016): Transcoding the Aesthetics of Noh Drama (Yayoi Uno Everett), and "They told me nothing/They gave me nothing": Approaching Erasure in The Industry's Sweet Land (Megan Steigerwald Ille).
  - Discussion I: Economics in the Field of Cultural Production, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 c; Chu, Allison; Pollock, Frances; Acon, Derrell; Diamond, Patrick (Theater Director); Harris, Maurice L.; Lang, David (David A.) (1957-01-08-); Romano, Aleks; 1 Computer File; 821 megabytes; Approximate running time: 61 mins
  - Discussion II: Developing New Themes in Opera, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 d; Kreuzer, Gundula Katharina; Du, Yun, 1977-; Kearney, Douglas (1974-); Lewis, George S.; Sharon, Yuval; 1 Computer File; 1.16 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 95 mins
  - Discussion III: Diversification through Collaboration?, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 e; Nyong'o, Tavia; Chacon, Raven (1977-12-); Du, Yun, 1977-; Kearney, Douglas (1974-); Lewis, George, 1952-; Lien, Mimi; Sharon, Yuval; 1 Computer File; 1.47 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 91 mins
  - Discussion IV: What To Do With the Canon? + Final Thoughts, 2021 May 8; YOST 2 f; André, Naomi Adele; Brooks, Daphne; Heard, Ethan; Moore, Latonia (1979-); Sharon, Yuval; 1 Computer File; 1.66 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 98 mins